# **Vlad Kanning**

# **Senior Product Designer**

Belgrade, Serbia · 38 161 632 65 43 · kanygin.uxd@gmail.com · https://www.linkedin.com/in/vlad-kan/

#### **SUMMARY**

Senior Product Designer with 11+ years in UX, UI, product, and web design, specializing in enterprise and B2B SaaS for industries like tech, oil, gas, and automotive. Led end-to-end design processes, from research to frontend support, in close collaboration with stakeholders. Managed simultaneous design for multiple products, ensuring usability, accessibility, and user satisfaction by following HCD, WCAG, and ISO 9241 standards.

## PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

# Senior UX Product Designer

Nov 2021 - to present

#### Luxoft, Belgrade, Serbia

Fortune 500 global tech development company, providing SaaS solutions to 420+ enterprises in 28 countries.

- Designed user experiences for SaaS products, focusing on user-centered design.
- Developed an AI-based contract management system, speeding up the process for 1,000 managers by 30%.
- Built over 50 features for a project management platform, reducing the use of third-party tools by 90%.
- Mentored 6 product teams, reducing UX errors by 50% and increasing development speed by 50%.
- Managed UX development for 7 projects with a 60% feature adoption rate.
- Implemented a design system that reduced frontend design errors by 40%.

Product Designer Aug 2020 – Nov 2021

### Eurasian Resources Group, Astana, Kazakhstan

One of the world's leading natural resources companies, major industry employer with 70,000 employees in 20 countries.

- Worked on three projects: Idea Management System, Enterprise Resource Planning System, and Website Builder.
- Improved the enterprise resource planning system by adding more than 20 functions and doubling the speed of processes.
- Completed a merger of over 15 services, eliminating 3 legacy platforms and reducing costs by 100%.
- Designed a website builder with over 80 customizable blocks, increasing administration speed by 90%.
- Created a design system that accelerated new system development by 50%.

Product Designer Feb 2020 – Nov 2021

#### Geonaft, Russia

Leading CIS B2B SaaS developer for the oil and gas industry, impacted in 5,500+ wells and fields worldwide.

- Designed over 30 features for 4 major products, attracting top-tier B2B clients and increasing software module sales by 10%.
- Created an MVP design for a top-tier client, outperforming 80% of competitors in a tender.
- Coached 3 product teams on UX improvements, increasing task velocity by 40%.
- Developed a design system for 6 products, speeding up the development process by 20%.

Product Designer Feb 2016 - Jan 2020

### Helmeton & Granovit, Russia

VR/AR/modern art startup & Real estate agency.

- Led the design and development of an e-commerce platform for contemporary artists, developing over 10 websites and generating 203 leads.
- Prototyped 2 AR products, securing 2 long-term commercial partnerships.
- Developed 4 promotional websites that resulted in 113 cold leads for real estate transactions.

Designer Jan 2011 - Nov 2018

# AIESEC, Russia

International NGO with 40,000 members in 100+ countries

• Led the design team in developing a branded product with an engaged community of 2,500 people.

# **PROJECT WORK**

UX / Product Designer 2020

#### Game Academy

EdTech startup that helps gamers transfer skills learned in games to real life.

• Created an MVP for a UK-based EdTech startup that secured investment.

### **EDUCATION**

University of Architecture, Design and Arts, Bachelor of Arts in Architecture, Russia, 2012 - 2017

# **LANGUAGES**

Russia: Native, English: Fluent.

# **SKILLS**

Product Design, UI/UX Design, Graphic Design, Figma, Sketch, Adobe XD, Adobe CS, Miro, HTML, CSS, UI Kit, Design System, UX Research, Usability Testing, User Interface Design, User Story.